A Guide to the Reynolds Family Papers, 1845-1869
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Reynolds Family Papers, 1845-1869
The Library of Virginia
22998
8 leaves and 29 pages
Reynolds Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1949, of Douglas Southall Freeman, Richmond, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Richard Furman Reynolds was born about 1817 in Charleston, South Carolina. He served as a colonel during the Civil War. After the war, he settled in Richmond, Virginia, where he died in 1870. His wife, Anna Hubbard Gardner Reynolds (1836-1910) was the daughter of James H. Gardner (1796-1877), a prominent merchant and president of the City Bank in Richmond. Thomas Caute Reynolds (1821-1887) was elected lieutenant governor of Missouri in 1860. When Missouri did not secede and join the Confederate States of America, he joined Governor Claiborne Jackson (1806-1862) as a government-in-exile. Upon Jackson's death, Reynolds became Missouri's governor-in-exile.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1845-1869, of the Reynolds family of Richmond, Virginia, and Charleston, South Carolina, consisting of bills of sale and receipts for the purchase of slaves; a letter, 20 [21] July 1861, Augusta P. Gardner (1804-1861), Richmond, to Anna Hubbard Gardner Reynolds (1836-1910), Charleston, South Carolina, concerning wartime conditions in Richmond, the first battle of Manassas, and a skirmish at Barboursville (West) Virginia; letters, 1866-1867, between Richard F. Reynolds (ca. 1817-1870) of Richmond, Henry B. Boutheneau (1797-1877) of Aiken, South Carolina, and Anna Morrison Jackson (1831-1915) of Charlotte, North Carolina, concerning Reynolds' efforts to have Boutheneau paint a miniature of Stonewall Jackson (1824-1863) for his widow Anna Jackson; and a letter, 18 April 1869, Jefferson Davis (1808-1889), London, England, to Thomas C. Reynolds (1821-1887), Missouri, discussing his exile and travels. The letters from Richard Reynolds are all manuscript copies.
Contents List
- Bill of sale, 31 December 1845, from Samuel Putney (1801-1880) of Richmond, Virginia, to James H. Gardner (1796-1877) of Richmond, Virginia, for Richard, a slave.
- Receipt, 2 May 1853, from Robert Alvis (1819-1894) of Richmond to Gardner for William Rush, a slave.
- Receipt, 15 December 1858, from W. P. Martin (1791-1863) of Richmond to Gardner for Harriet and her child, slaves.
- Letter, 20 [21] July 1861, from Augusta P. Gardner (1804-1861) of Richmond to Anna Hubbard Gardner Reynolds (1836-1910) of Charleston, South Carolina, concerning wartime conditions in Richmond, the first battle of Manassas, and a skirmish at Barboursville (West) Virginia.
- Letter, 19 October 1866, from Richard F. Reynolds (ca. 1817-1870) of Richmond to Henry B. Bounetheau (1797-1877) of Aiken, South Carolina, asking if Bounetheau would paint a miniature of Thomas J. "Stonewall" Jackson (1824-1863) for his widow Anna Morrison Jackson (1831-1915).
- Letter, 28 October 1866, from Bounetheau to Reynolds stating he would do a miniature for $100 in gold.
- Letter, 31 October 1866, from Reynolds to Bounetheau thanking Bounetheau for his terms and informing him that Reynolds is forwarding the letter to Mrs. Jackson.
- Letter, 31 October 1866, from Reynolds to Anna Morrison Jackson of Charlotte, North Carolina, informing her of his negociations with Bounetheau for a miniature of Stonewall Jackson.
- Letter, 28 November 1866, from Mrs. Jackson to Reynolds, thanking him for his efforts, but regretting that she is unable to afford the cost.
- Letter, 1 January 1867, from Reynolds to Mrs. Jackson concerning her inability to pay for a portrait and enclosing a copy of a letter to Bounetheau informing him of this news.
- Letter, 21 January 1867, from Bounetheau to Reynolds, offering to paint the miniature for Mrs. Jackson and allowing her to pay when convenient.
- Letter, 18 April 1869, from Jefferson Davis (1808-1889), in London, England, to Thomas C. Reynolds (1821-1887) of Missouri, sending greetings and informing Reynolds of his exile and travels.